<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<resources>

    <string name="app_name">DNDNextGen</string>

    <string name="import_character_init">"This is not supported yet, check back soon!</string>

    <string name="create_char_init">this is the character creator</string>
    <string name="navigation_drawer_open">Open navigation drawer</string>
    <string name="navigation_drawer_close">Close navigation drawer</string>
    <string name="action_example">Example action</string>
    <string name="action_settings">Settings</string>

    <string name="welcome"> Welcome to DND Next Gen\n\n Check the left-side navigation drawer to begin!</string>

    <string name="view_character_init">view character here</string>

    <string name="character_create_init">create character here</string>


    <string name="menu_init">Welcome to DND Next Gen</string>

    <string-array name="race_array">
        <item>human</item>
        <item>elf</item>
        <item>halfling</item>
        <item>half-orc</item>
        <item>half-elf</item>
        <item>dwarf</item>
        <item>tiefling</item>
        <item>eladrin</item>
        <item>dragon-born</item>
    </string-array>

    <string name="human_text">Humans\n\n Humans possess exceptional drive and a great capacity to endure and expand, and as such are currently the dominant race in the world. Their empires and nations are vast, sprawling things, and the citizens of these societies carve names for themselves with the strength of their sword arms and the power of their spells. Humanity is best characterized by its tumultuousness and diversity, and human cultures run the gamut from savage but honorable tribes to decadent, devil-worshiping noble families in the most cosmopolitan cities. Humans\' curiosity and ambition often triumph over their predilection for a sedentary lifestyle, and many leave their homes to explore the innumerable forgotten corners of the world or lead mighty armies to conquer their neighbors, simply because they can.</string>
    <string name="elf_text">Elves \n\nThe long-lived elves are children of the natural world, similar in many superficial ways to fey creatures, though with key differences. While fey are truly linked to the flora and fauna of their homes, existing as the nearly immortal voices and guardians of the wilderness, elves are instead mortals who are in tune with the natural world around them. Elves seek to live in balance with the wild and understand it better than most other mortals. Some of this understanding is mystical, but an equal part comes from the elves\' long lifespans, which in turn gives them long-ranging outlooks. Elves can expect to remain active in the same locale for centuries. By necessity, they must learn to maintain sustainable lifestyles, and this is most easily done when they work with nature, rather than attempting to bend it to their will. However, their links to nature are not entirely driven by pragmatism. Elves\' bodies slowly change over time, taking on a physical representation of their mental and spiritual states, and those who dwell in a region for a long period of time find themselves physically adapting to match their surroundings, most noticeably taking on coloration that reflects the local environment.</string>
    <string name="eladrin_text">Eladrin \n\nEladrin once lived in the magical beauty of the twilight courts. They are people who value beauty and splendor over anything else. Much like their elven brothers, Eladrin often appear as being arrogant and elitist to other races. Unlike elves, however, Eladrin are much more reserved and cold, typically appearing more aloof and absorbed in their own thoughts and meditations. \n\nEladrin are accustomed to showing their feelings in the form of an art rather than in words: painting, singing and dancing are the primary ways in which they express themselves, which is why they mostly seem cold and detached when speaking. However, even when speaking a strange charm seems to radiate from them.\n\n An Eladrin\'s height is usually between 5\′\ 5\″ and 6\′ 2\″. They are slim, weighing in between 130 and 180 pounds, and even the strongest simply look athletic rather than muscle-bound. They usually have pale complexions and long straight hair, which is often pale blue, silver or golden blond. Their ears are long and pointed, and their eyes are pearly orbs of vibrant blue, deep purple, emerald green or bright yellow, lacking pupils.
.</string>
    <string name="half_elf_text">Half-Elves \n\nElves have long drawn the covetous gazes of other races. Their generous lifespans, magical affinity, and inherent grace each contribute to the admiration or bitter envy of their neighbors. Of all their traits, however, none so entrance their human associates as their beauty. Since the two races first came into contact with each other, humans have held up elves as models of physical perfection, seeing in these fair folk idealized versions of themselves. For their part, many elves find humans attractive despite their comparatively barbaric ways, and are drawn to the passion and impetuosity with which members of the younger race play out their brief lives. Sometimes this mutual infatuation leads to romantic relationships. Though usually short-lived, even by human standards, such trysts may lead to the birth of half-elves, a race descended from two cultures yet inheritor of neither. Half-elves can breed with one another, but even these “pure-blood” half-elves tend to be viewed as bastards by humans and elves alike. Caught between destiny and derision, half-elves often view themselves as the middle children of the world.</string>
    <string name="half_orc_text">Half-Orcs \n\nAs seen by civilized races, half-orcs are monstrosities, the result of perversion and violence—whether or not this is actually true. Half-orcs are rarely the result of loving unions, and as such are usually forced to grow up hard and fast, constantly fighting for protection or to make names for themselves. Half-orcs as a whole resent this treatment, and rather than play the part of the victim, they tend to lash out, unknowingly confirming the biases of those around them. A few feared, distrusted, and spat-upon half-orcs manage to surprise their detractors with great deeds and unexpected wisdom—though sometimes it\'s easier just to crack a few skulls. Some half-orcs spend their entire lives proving to full-blooded orcs that they are just as fierce. Others opt for trying to blend into human society, constantly demonstrating that they aren\'t monsters. Their need to always prove themselves worthy encourages half-orcs to strive for power and greatness within the society around them.</string>
    <string name="halfling_text">Halflings \n\n Optimistic and cheerful by nature, blessed with uncanny luck, and driven by a powerful wanderlust, halflings make up for their short stature with an abundance of bravado and curiosity. At once excitable and easy-going, halflings like to keep an even temper and a steady eye on opportunity, and are not as prone to violent or emotional outbursts as some of the more volatile races. Even in the jaws of catastrophe, halflings almost never lose their sense of humor. Their ability to find humor in the absurd, no matter how dire the situation, often allows halflings to distance themselves ever so slightly from the dangers that surround them. This sense of detachment can also help shield them from terrors that might immobilize their allies.\n\nHalflings are inveterate opportunists. They firmly believe they can turn any situation to their advantage, and sometimes gleefully leap into trouble without any solid plan to extricate themselves if things go awry. Often unable to physically defend themselves from the rigors of the world, they know when to bend with the wind and when to hide away. Yet halflings\' curiosity often overwhelms their good sense, leading to poor decisions and narrow escapes. While harsh experience sometimes teaches halflings a measure of caution, it rarely makes them completely lose faith in their luck or stop believing that the universe, in some strange way, exists for their entertainment and would never really allow them to come to harm. Though their curiosity drives them to seek out new places and experiences, halflings possess a strong sense of hearth and home, often spending above their means to enhance the comforts of domestic life. Without a doubt, halflings enjoy luxury and comfort, but they have equally strong reasons to make their homes a showcase. Halflings consider this urge to devote time, money, and energy toward improving their dwellings a sign of both respect for strangers and affection for their loved ones. Whether for their own blood kin, cherished friends, or honored guests, halflings make their homes beautiful in order to express their feelings toward those they welcome inside. Even traveling halflings typically decorate their wagons or carry a few cherished keepsakes to adorn their campsites.</string>
    <string name="dwarf_text">Dwarves \n\n Dwarves are a stoic but stern race, ensconced in cities carved from the hearts of mountains and fiercely determined to repel the depredations of savage races like orcs and goblins. More than any other race, dwarves have acquired a reputation as dour and humorless artisans of the earth. It could be said that their history shapes the dark disposition of many dwarves, for they reside in high mountains and dangerous realms below the earth, constantly at war with giants, goblins, and other such horrors.\n\nDwarves are lovers of history and tradition, and their long lifespan leads to far less in the way of generational shifts in attitudes, styles, fashions, and trends than shorter-lived races exhibit. If a thing is not broken, they do not fix it or change it; and if it is broken, they fix it rather than replace it. Thrifty as a rule, dwarves are loath to discard anything unless it is truly ruined and unable to be fixed. At the same time, dwarves meticulous, near-obsessive attention to detail and durability in their craftsmanship makes that a rare occurrence, as the things they make are built to last. As a result, buildings, artwork, tools, housewares, garments, weapons, and virtually everything else made by dwarves still sees regular use at an age when such items would be relegated to museum pieces, dusty antique shelves, or junkyard fodder by other races. Taken together, these traits create the impression that dwarves are a race frozen in time.</string>

    <!-- TODO: Remove or change this placeholder text -->
    <string name="hello_blank_fragment">Hello blank fragment</string>
    <string name="title_activity_character_create">CharacterCreateActivity</string>

    <string name="hello_world">Hello world!</string>
    <string name="drawer_open">Open</string>
    <string name="drawer_close">@string/menu_init</string>
    <string name="title_activity_double_drawer">DoubleDrawerActivity</string>
    <string name="title_activity_view_character">ViewCharacter</string>
    <string name="title_activity_import_character">ImportCharacter</string>


</resources>
